questions:
  - id: shell-setup-q1
    category: "Shell Setup: Aliases & Autocomplete"
    prompt: "Shell aliases are shortcuts for longer commands, saving you from typing long commands repeatedly. A common alias is `k` for `kubectl`, which lets you run commands like `k get pods`. Create the `k` alias now."
    response: "alias k=kubectl"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/quick-reference/#:~:text=You%20can%20also%20use%20a,that%20also%20works%20with%20completion"
  - id: shell-setup-q8
    category: "Shell Setup: Aliases & Autocomplete"
    prompt: "Enable kubectl autocomplete in your shell"
    response: |
      source <(kubectl completion bash)
      complete -F __start_kubectl k
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/quick-reference/#:~:text=BASH"
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/quick-reference/#:~:text=alias%20k%3Dkubectl%20complete%20,F%20__start_kubectl%20k"
  - id: shell-setup-q9
    category: "Shell Setup: Aliases & Autocomplete"
    prompt: "List pods using the 'k' alias"
    response: "k get pods"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/quick-reference/#:~:text=,List%20all%20pods%20in%20the"
  - id: shell-setup-q10
    category: "Shell Setup: Aliases & Autocomplete"
    prompt: "List replicasets using the short alias"
    response: "k get rs"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=,apps%2Fv1%20true%20StatefulSet"
  - id: shell-setup-q11
    category: "Shell Setup: Aliases & Autocomplete"
    prompt: "List daemonsets using the short alias"
    response: "k get ds"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=,apps%2Fv1%20true%20ReplicaSet"
  - id: shell-setup-q12
    category: "Shell Setup: Aliases & Autocomplete"
    prompt: "List services using the 'k' alias"
    response: "k get svc"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/quick-reference/#:~:text=,all%20pods%20in%20the%20current"
  - id: shell-setup-q13
    category: "Shell Setup: Aliases & Autocomplete"
    prompt: "List ConfigMaps using the short alias"
    response: "k get cm"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=,v1%20true%20Endpoints"
  - id: shell-setup-q14
    category: "Shell Setup: Aliases & Autocomplete"
    prompt: "List secrets using the short alias"
    response: "k get secret"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=,v1%20true%20Secret"
  - id: shell-setup-q15
    category: "Shell Setup: Aliases & Autocomplete"
    prompt: "List HorizontalPodAutoscalers using the short alias"
    response: "k get hpa"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=,batch%2Fv1%20true%20CronJob"
  - id: shell-setup-q16
    category: "Shell Setup: Aliases & Autocomplete"
    prompt: "List Ingresses using the short alias"
    response: "k get ing"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=PriorityLevelConfiguration%20,networking.k8s.io%2Fv1%20true%20NetworkPolicy"
  - id: shell-setup-q17
    category: "Shell Setup: Aliases & Autocomplete"
    prompt: "List NetworkPolicies using the short alias"
    response: "k get netpol"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=PriorityLevelConfiguration%20,node.k8s.io%2Fv1%20false%20RuntimeClass"
  - id: shell-setup-q18
    category: "Shell Setup: Aliases & Autocomplete"
    prompt: "List ServiceAccounts using the short alias"
    response: "k get sa"
    links:
      - "https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubectl/#:~:text=,v1%20true%20Service"
